<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on ICASSP 2026: Human-like Spoken Dialogue Systems Challenge</title>
    <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on ICASSP 2026: Human-like Spoken Dialogue Systems Challenge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>General description</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/homepage_sections/general_description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/homepage_sections/general_description/</guid>
      <description>Challenge Call Have you been following the recent buzz around the impressive performance of next-generation voice dialogue models like GPT-4o, Doubao, and the newly released GPT-Realtime? They are not only lightning-fast and expressive but also enable seamless multimodal interactions, making conversations feel remarkably human.
From the traditional “clunky AI” to today’s “AI assistant,” the evolution of voice dialogue systems has been nothing short of astonishing. But just how far are we from achieving truly “natural human-machine dialogue”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/homepage_sections/leaderboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/homepage_sections/leaderboard/</guid>
      <description>Registration Teams can register by the google form: https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdRrlfqrhh8QhOxtKMr03AxnnX14md_EwFuIuMt-Hf4fhhARA/viewform?usp=header
Reminder! Please use your institutional or corporate email address to register, and avoid using personal email accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timeline</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/homepage_sections/timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/homepage_sections/timeline/</guid>
      <description>Timeline August 20, 2025: Registration opens September 29, 2025: Release of training set, validation set, and baseline system(delay for a few days) November 10, 2025: Release of test set November 25, 2025: Submission deadline December 7, 2025: Deadline for submitting 2-page papers to ICASSP 2026 (invited teams only) January 11, 2026: Notification of acceptance for 2-page ICASSP 2026 papers January 18, 2026: Submission of final version of papers May 4–8, 2026: ICASSP 2026 Conference, Barcelona, Spain Official Competition Rules 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leaderboard</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task1/leaderboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task1/leaderboard/</guid>
      <description> All results Group nameSubmission number subjects mean subjects std total score </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>leaderboard</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task2/leaderboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task2/leaderboard/</guid>
      <description> All results Group nameSubmission number subjects mean subjects std Band 0 mean Band 1 mean Band 2 mean Band 3 mean Band 4 mean Band 5 mean Band 6 mean Band 7 mean Band 8 mean Band 9 mean total score </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizers</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/homepage_sections/organizers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/homepage_sections/organizers/</guid>
      <description>Organizers The challenge is organized by a distinguished team of researchers:
Lei Xie, Professor, Northwestern Polytechnical University Shuai Wang, Associate Professor, Nanjing University Haizhou Li, Professor, Chinese University of Hong Kong Eng Siong Chng, Professor, Nanyang Technological University Hung-yi Lee, Professor, Natioanl Taiwan University Chao Zhang, Assistant Professor, Tsinghua University Guangzhi Sun, Junior Research Fellow, University of Cambridge Xixin Wu, Assistant Professor, Chinese University of Hong Kong Longshuai Xiao, Huawei Technologies Zihan Zhang, Huawei Technologies Xinsheng Wang, Soul AI Lab Hui Bu, AISHELL Xin Xu， AISHELL Zhixian Zhao, Northwestern Polytechnical University Hongfei Xue, Northwestern Polytechnical University Xuelong Geng, Northwestern Polytechnical University GuoJian Li, Northwestern Polytechnical University Shuiyuan Wang, Northwestern Polytechnical University Contact For any inquiries, please contact:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Set Track 1</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task1/test_set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task1/test_set/</guid>
      <description>todo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Set Track 2</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task2/test_set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task2/test_set/</guid>
      <description>todo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track 1: Emotional Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task1/description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task1/description/</guid>
      <description>Challenge Tasks Task 1: Emotional Trajectory Detection - Evaluate the model&amp;rsquo;s ability to accurately identify and concisely summarize a user&amp;rsquo;s emotional changes throughout a multi-turn conversation. Task 2: Emotional Reasoning - Evaluate the model&amp;rsquo;s ability to perceive the underlying causes of a user&amp;rsquo;s emotions. Task 3: Empathy Assessment - Evaluate the model&amp;rsquo;s ability to generate empathetic responses in both text and audio formats. The final ranking will be determined based on the comprehensive score of the above three core tasks, and the specific weights of each task will be announced in subsequent stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track 2: Full-Duplex Interaction</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task2/description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/task2/description/</guid>
      <description>Challenge Tasks The full-duplex benchmark primarily encompasses two major Scenarios: interruption and rejection.
1. Interruption Scenarios: Follow-up Questions: The user poses a follow-up question based on the model’s previous response, interrupting the ongoing output. The model should promptly address the user’s follow-up inquiry. Negation / Dissatisfaction: The user expresses dissatisfaction or disagreement with the model’s response using negative statements, interrupting the model mid-sentence. The model should appropriately react to the user’s negation or dissatisfaction in a timely manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/faq/</guid>
      <description>General Information Q: Unable to register using Google Form
A: If registration via Google Form fails, users in mainland China can also sign up using the following link: [Tencent Docs] ICASSP 2026 HumDial Challenge Registration https://docs.qq.com/form/page/DY2tvT3FvWnRMZXRp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aslp-lab.github.io/HumDial-Challenge/registration/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
